Now we're going to create a context which will be a global state for application, so the data that
you have in the context state will be available for the entire application.
So when the user logs in, we get the user and token so that when we were put in the context.
All right.
So let's go ahead and query context.
So it's a planful folder in the root directory.
Looks good at file.
And let's call it context, actually, let's create a folder helix grid full context.
And instead, we create a context file called both parties.
By the way, you can have more than one context stream if we need later, we can create another context
as well, so we just put it into a folder.
Now first, let's import react,
and we are going to use state, you state.
That's where we going to store the user and told them to use state use effect.
Also, we'll be using later.
So let me invert.
So we import react, we import excuse.
We also need to import essence stories because if the user and token is saved in the local stores,
we want to grab that and populate this state.
In this context, so that way, if there is any data available when the issue could reload, a user
returns the application.
We can grab that data from there and then, yeah.
So that they don't have to keep logging in.
It's time.
So that means let me just go to one of the screen signing just so that I can copy this import command.
It's back to context after we import async stories as well sort of create a context, we need to use
the use context hope so we can input that to use context.
But I choose not to use context to create context, create context and then to study using the create
context.
We can execute that and put in a variable, let's call it context equals to create context.
And this is a function we give.
We just execute this function.
And that would give us the context.
I guess we got the context.
Now we need to improvise as well.
Comms provider equals.
So here we can create a state just like in a regular React component.
So const state said state equals to use state.
And here in this state, we want to store the user and token right.
So user, we give the default value of not the empty object and token will be the type of string.
So we've got the state and now we want to load the user and token from the local storage by default.
Okay.
So whenever the application is ready to use effect, it takes a functional argument and second argument
the dependency.
We leave it empty.
So here we want to load the data from the local stories using async stories and then we can to put that
in this state so that we, if there is any value in the async stories that will be populated in the
state here.
So let me create a function load from async stories and construct async.
So here, let me put the the target that we get from missing stories into this variable.
So the point is the stories don't get item, get item by the name of at.
If you remember, we have saved the response by the name of oath when we sign in and sign up.
So we grab that put in a very raw data.
Now, once you give this data, we have to convert it into JavaScript object because we saved it as
Jason using this and string and fire right now to start using it as JavaScript object, we can put it
in a bit.
We can put it in a variable.
It's called async stories.
As Jason Pass, we're going to pass this and object to.
This and other disaster, this in Paris and give the data to this function that will give us the objects
in the this variable right now, since we can put it in state first, we spread the state.
Whatever data we have in the state, we spread it out and then we update.
Now we update the user with the data we get from the essence.
First is don't use it and then stop them and stop.
I said that we we grab this value and then put in the state and now we need to execute this function.
Otherwise, nothing happens here.
Let's execute using the parentheses.
All right.
So you defect on this issue.
So is that application loose?
This will get fired.
And as a result, we will give the user a token in the state.
So that means we can start using context now.
So all you have to do is export export of context and also provide.
So do started using this one.
Actually, we have to do one, the thing you have to return something, right?
And then what are?
We're going to wrap our entire entire application using.
Author provided and that will provide the these functions stint and then sends it to any other compliance.
For example, those components will be accessible as children process.
OK.
So you can do props and profit or children or even better, just destructor street children.
All right.
So you want to return the children component, which can be anything like sanding?
Sign up any other piece.
They are.
We will wrap big user with us writing.
All right.
So when you return.
We are going to use you the context.
What context don't go by the time we get this access to this was provided, so we we return what context
provided.
And here?
What do you want to provide?
We want to provide the value that will be this standard substance in this competition.
So this is the state and of the state.
This is the front and center step ahead.
So both of these, if we can pass as a value to any of the components, that's all we want, right?
So then this state will be global accessible anywhere using the program and from any company, you can
easily access the state and unrealistic.
So you pass the value like that and then you return children.
Children come from.
All right.
Simple as that.
That's our context.
Now later, we'll come back and configure exit assessment so that you don't have to send the token.
It's time when you make a request so you can configure excuse so that it will be the token will be sent
in the Harris globally.
All right.
So we've come back to that at the moment.
We have the context.
Now we can start using it.
So let's go to where do you want to access this one?
So at the moment?
Let's go to emptiest test, and we have the navigation here, right?
So this is where you want to input the context provided and wrap everything in.
So we import off for wider
destruction,
ultraviolet from context and then.
Yeah.
All this stuff, navigate to a wrap with three of our.
All right, that so once you do that, the value they stood in said state will be accessible to any
other components that you can give this a try to try that let's create a screen.
Let's do that in the next lecture, let's create a home screen and let's try accessing the state the
context just so that we can see that everything is working.